reverb.com 2018-08-28

# Privacy Policy | Reverb.com | Reverb

## YOU CAN ACCESS OUR COOKIES SPECIFIC POLICY HERE

1\. Introduction  
2\. Children Under the Age of 18  
3\. Information We Collect About You  
4\. Information You Provide to Us  
5\. Information We Collect Through Automatic Data Collection Technologies  
6\. How We Use Your Information  
7\. Disclosure of Your Information  
8\. Choices About How We Use and Disclose Your Information  
9\. Accessing and Correcting Your Information  
10\. Third-Party Use of Cookies and Other Tracking Technologies  
11\. Data Security  
12\. Data Retention  
13\. Changes to Our Privacy Policy  
14\. Data Breach  
15\. Privacy Shield  
16\. Contact Information

### 1\. Introduction

Reverb.com, LLC, its affiliated companies (“Reverb” or “we” or “us”) and the associated websites were formed to create a community for musicians, collectors, enthusiasts, dealers and the just-plain-curious to gather in a marketplace fully dedicated to buying and selling instruments, gear, equipment and musical recordings.  Therefore, the privacy of all of our members and stakeholders - your privacy - is something we take extremely seriously.  This policy details how we treat the personal information that we collect, what settings we provide for you to control how your information is used on Reverb, and how you can contact us with any questions or concerns. This policy is not a contract between Reverb and its users, but is merely a recitation of Reverb policies.

This policy describes the types of information we may collect from you or that you may provide when you visit the websites [reverb.com](https://www.reverb.com/), [lp.reverb.com](https://lp.reverb.com/) or any of their affiliated websites (our “Website”) and our practices for collecting, using, maintaining, protecting, and disclosing that information. It also applies to information we collect: (a) in email, text, and other electronic messages between you and this Website; (b) through mobile and desktop applications you download from this Website, which provide dedicated non-browser-based interaction between you and this Website; (c) when you interact with our advertising and applications on third-party websites and services, if those applications or advertising include links to this policy; and (d) through any other sources associated with the Website. 

The policy does not apply to information collected by: (a) us offline; or (b) any third party, including through any application or content (including advertising) that may link to or be accessible from or on the Website. 

Please read this policy carefully to understand our policies and practices regarding your information and how we will treat it. By accessing or using the Website, you expressly agree to this policy. This policy may change from time to time. Your continued use of this Website after we make changes is deemed to be acceptance of those changes, so please check the policy periodically for updates. 

### 2\. Children Under the Age of 18

Reverb’s Terms of Use require all account owners to be at least 18 years of age (or have the permission and supervision of a responsible parent or legal guardian). Accordingly, this policy does not discuss use of our Website or services by minors. 

### 3\. Information We Collect About You

We collect several types of information from and about users of our Website, including information: (a) by which you may be personally identified, such as name, postal address, e-mail address, telephone number, or any other information the Website collects that is defined as personal or personally identifiable information under an applicable law or any other identifier by which you may be contacted online or offline. Depending on which services you choose to use, Reverb may require additional information, such as a shop name, billing information (including billing address, phone number, credit card information), a mobile telephone number, a physical mailing address, and/or payment information. As a shop owner if you choose to enable [Reverb Payments](https://reverb.com/page/payouts-bucks-giftcards), Reverb may require information such as your social security number or tax ID, date of birth, bank account information and/or credit card information in order to verify your identity and provide this service to you (collectively “personal information”); (b) that is about you but individually does not identify you, such as username or alias; and/or (c) about your internet connection, the equipment you use to access our Website and usage details. 

We collect this information: (a) directly from you when you provide it to us; or (b) automatically as you navigate through the site. Information collected automatically may include usage details, IP addresses, and information collected through cookies, web beacons, and other tracking technologies. 

### 4\. Information You Provide to Us 

We may also collect information from you through our Website which may include: (a) information that you provide by filling in forms; (b) information provided at the time of registering to use our Website; (c) information when you enter a promotion sponsored by us; (d) information when you report a problem with our Website; (e) records and copies of your correspondence (including email addresses), if you contact us; (f) your responses to surveys that we might ask you to complete for research purposes; (g) details of transactions you carry out through our Website and of the fulfillment of your orders; (h) financial information before placing an order through our Website; and (i) your search queries on the Website. 

You also may provide information to be published or displayed (hereinafter, “posted”) on public areas of the Website, or transmitted to other users of the Website or third parties (collectively, “User Contributions”). Your User Contributions are posted on and transmitted to others at your own risk. Although we limit access to certain pages and you may set certain privacy settings for such information by logging into your account profile, please be aware that no security measures are perfect or impenetrable. Additionally, we cannot control the actions of other users of the Website with whom you may choose to share your User Contributions. Therefore, we cannot and do not guarantee that your User Contributions will not be viewed by unauthorized persons. 

### 5\. Information We Collect Through Automatic Data Collection Technologies

As you navigate through and interact with our Website, we may use automatic data collection technologies to collect certain information about your equipment, browsing actions, and patterns, including: (a) details of your visits to our Website, including traffic data, location data, logs, and other communication data and the resources that you access and use on the Website; and (b) information about your computer and internet connection, including your IP address, operating system, and browser type. 

The information we collect automatically is statistical data and does not include personal information, but we may maintain it or associate it with personal information we collect in other ways or receive from third parties. It helps us to improve our Website and to deliver a better and more personalized service, including by enabling us to: (a) estimate our audience size and usage patterns; (b) store information about your preferences, allowing us to customize our Website according to your individual interests; (c) speed up your searches; or (d) recognize you when you return to our Website. 

The technologies we use for this automatic data collection may include: (a) Cookies (or browser cookies). A cookie is a small file placed on the hard drive of your computer. You may refuse to accept browser cookies by activating the appropriate setting on your browser. However, if you select this setting you may be unable to access certain parts of our Website. Unless you have adjusted your browser setting so that it will refuse cookies, our system will issue cookies when you direct your browser to our Website; (b) Flash Cookies. Certain features of our Website may use local stored objects (or Flash cookies) to collect and store information about your preferences and navigation to, from, and on our Website. Flash cookies are not managed by the same browser settings as are used for browser cookies; (c) Web Beacons. Pages of our the Website may contain small electronic files known as web beacons (also referred to as clear gifs, pixel tags, and single-pixel gifs) that permit Reverb, for example, to count users who have visited those pages or opened an email and for other related website statistics (for example, recording the popularity of certain website content and verifying system and server integrity); (d) Google Analytics, a web analytics service provided by Google Inc. (“Google”). Google uses Cookies to help analyze the use of the Website. The information generated by the Cookie about your use of the Site is sent to a Google server in the United States and stored there. Please note, that your IP address will be truncated by our systems before sending the data to a Google server. Thereby you will remain anonymous as an individual user. Google will use this information to evaluate your use of the Site, compile reports on Site activity and provide other Site activity and internet related services. In addition, Google may also transfer this information to third parties if required by law or if third parties process the information on Google’s behalf. By using this Site, you consent to the processing of data about you by Google in the manner described and for the aforementioned purpose. More information about Google Analytics can be found [here](https://www.google.com/analytics/#?modal_active=none). See more about automatic data collection, cookies and opt-ing out in our [Cookies Policy](https://reverb.com/page/cookies-policy)

We do not collect personal information automatically, but we may tie this information to personal information about you that we collect from other sources or you provide to us. 

To read more and opt-out, you can visit the [following](http://www.criteo.com/privacy/)

### 6\. How We Use Your Information

We use information that we collect about you or that you provide to us, including any personal information: (a) to present our Website and its contents to you; (b) to provide you with information, products, or services that you request from us; (c) to fulfill any other purpose for which you provide it; (d) to provide you with notices about your membership; (e) to carry out our obligations and enforce any rights arising from any contracts entered into on the Website, including for billing and collection; (f) to notify you about changes to our Website or any products or services we offer or provide though it; (g) to allow you to participate in interactive features on our Website; (h) in any other way we may describe when you provide the information; (i) for any other purpose with your consent; (j) we may also use your information to contact you about our own and third-parties’ goods and services that may be of interest to you; and (k) we may use the information we have collected from you to enable us to display advertisements to our advertisers’ target audiences. Even though we do not disclose your personal information for these purposes without your consent, if you click on or otherwise interact with an advertisement, the advertiser may assume that you meet its target criteria. 

### 7\. Disclosure of Your Information

We may disclose aggregated information about our users, and information that does not identify any individual, without restriction. 

We may disclose personal information that we collect or you provide as described in this privacy policy: (a) to our subsidiaries and affiliates; (b) to contractors, service providers, and other third parties we use to support our business and who are bound by contractual obligations to keep personal information confidential and use it only for the purposes for which we disclose it to them; (c) to a buyer or other successor in the event of a merger, divestiture, restructuring, reorganization, dissolution, or other sale or transfer of some or all of Reverb’s assets, whether as a going concern or as part of bankruptcy, liquidation, or similar proceeding, in which personal information held by Reverb about our Website users is among the assets transferred; (d) to fulfill the purpose for which you provide it; (e) for any other purpose disclosed by us when you provide the information; and (f) with your consent. 

We may also disclose your personal information: (a) to comply with any court order, law, or legal process, including to respond to any government or regulatory request; (b) to enforce or apply our [Terms of Use](https://reverb.com/page/terms) and other agreements; or (c) if we believe disclosure is necessary or appropriate to protect the rights, property, or safety of Reverb, our customers, or others. This includes exchanging information with other companies and organizations for the purposes of fraud protection and credit risk reduction. 

### 8\. Choices About How We Use and Disclose Your Information

We strive to provide you with choices regarding the personal information you provide to us. We have created mechanisms to provide you with the following control over your information: 

Tracking Technologies and Advertising. You can set your browser to refuse all or some browser cookies, or to alert you when cookies are being sent. If you disable or refuse cookies, please note that some parts of this site may then be inaccessible or not function properly. 

Messages from Reverb: 

\- On occasion, Reverb will send you messages. The default required form of communication is email. However, we may choose to offer additional ways to reach you, such as through text messaging (SMS) or physical mail. By using Reverb’s site, you hereby agree that you have provided prior express written consent to receive messages, whether email or SMS, and acknowledge that you have an established business relationship (EBR) with Reverb. You may opt out of these messages by contacting [Customer Service](https://reverb.com/page/contact). 

\- Some messages from Reverb are service-related and required for members. Examples of service-related messages include, but are not limited to: a welcome/confirmation email when you register your account, notification of an order, or correspondence with Reverb’s support team. These messages are not promotional in nature. You may opt out of these messages by contacting [Customer Service](https://reverb.com/page/contact). 

\- As a member, Reverb may also send you messages related to certain features on the site or your activity. Reverb may also send you news or updates about changes to our site or services. By default, members will receive these messages via email, but you may choose to opt-out of getting certain emails under your account settings. You may opt out of these messages by contacting [Customer Service](https://reverb.com/page/contact). 

\- Reverb offers optional email newsletters. You must opt-in or subscribe to begin receiving newsletters, and subscription is available to both members and non-members. Members may subscribe or unsubscribe from optional newsletters under your account settings or by following the instructions contained in the newsletter emails. Non-members may subscribe by providing an email address, which will only be used by Reverb for these newsletters. Non-members may unsubscribe from newsletters by following the instructions contained in the newsletter emails. 

### 9\. Accessing and Correcting Your Information

You can review and change your personal information by logging into the Website and visiting your account profile page. 

You may also send us an email at admin@reverb.com to request access to, correct or delete any personal information that you have provided to us. We cannot delete your personal information except by also deleting your user account. We may not accommodate a request to change information if we believe the change would violate any law or legal requirement or cause the information to be incorrect. 

If you delete your User Contributions from the Website, copies of your User Contributions may remain viewable in cached and archived pages, or might have been copied or stored by other Website users. 

### 10\. Third-Party Use of Cookies and Other Tracking Technologies

Some content or applications, including advertisements, on the Website are served by third-parties, including advertisers, ad networks and servers, content providers, and application providers. These third parties may use cookies alone or in conjunction with web beacons or other tracking technologies to collect information about you when you use our website. The information they collect may be associated with your personal information or they may collect information, including personal information, about your online activities over time and across different websites and other online services. They may use this information to provide you with interest-based (behavioral) advertising or other targeted content. 

We do not control these third parties’ tracking technologies or how they may be used. If you have any questions about an advertisement or other targeted content, you should contact the responsible provider directly. 

### 11\. Data Security

We have implemented measures designed to secure your personal information from accidental loss and from unauthorized access, use, alteration, and disclosure. All information you provide to us is stored on our secure servers behind firewalls. Any payment transactions and other sensitive information will be encrypted using secure socket layer (SSL) technology. Reverb follows generally accepted industry standards to protect the personal information submitted to us, both during transmission and once Reverb receives it. 

The safety and security of your information also depends on you. Where we have given you (or where you have chosen) a password for access to certain parts of our Website, you are responsible for keeping this password confidential. We ask you not to share your password with anyone. We urge you to be careful about giving out information in public areas of the Website like message boards. The information you share in public areas may be viewed by any user of the Website. 

Unfortunately, the transmission of information via the internet is not completely secure. Although we do our best to protect your personal information, we cannot guarantee the security of your personal information transmitted to our Website. Any transmission of personal information is at your own risk. We are not responsible for circumvention of any privacy settings or security measures contained on the Website. 

### 12\. Data Retention

Reverb will retain your information for as long as your account is active or as needed to provide you services.  If you no longer want Reverb to use your information to provide you services, you may close your account. After closing your account, Reverb will solely retain and use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements. 

### 13\. Changes to Our Privacy Policy

It is our policy to post any changes we make to our privacy policy on this page. You are responsible for ensuring we have an up-to-date active and deliverable email address for you, and for periodically visiting our Website and this privacy policy to check for any changes. 

### 14\. Data Breach

If you suspect a data breach, please contact us at admin@reverb.com or by contacting Customer Engagement at 1-888-726-2728.

### 15\. Privacy Shield

Reverb is committed to complying with the provisions of the EU - U.S. Privacy Shield framework. You can find information about Privacy Shield [here](https://www.privacyshield.gov/welcome). Our applicable Data Protection Authority can be contacted [here](https://autoriteitpersoonsgegevens.nl/en). Enforcement in the U.S. is provided by the Federal Trade Commission. As a user, you have the right to access your personal data and Reverb must disclose your personal data in response to a lawful request from public authorities. You may bring any complaint to Reverb by contacting us using the Contact Information set forth below and we will respond within 45 days. If a complaint has not been resolved, it will be submitted to arbitration pursuant to the arbitration provisions set forth in Reverb's [Terms of Use](https://reverb.com/page/reverb-dot-com-and-reverb-lp-terms-of-use). 

### 16\. Contact Information

If you have questions or suggestions you can contact us, by sending an email to admin@reverb.com, or writing to: Reverb Customer Service - Privacy Policy, 3345 N Lincoln Ave, Chicago, IL 60657. 

Last modified: March 8, 2018
